# **Liam Watts**

lwat0536@uni.sydney.edu.au | 0478 214 655| linkedIn/liam-watts | github/Wattsy2020

## **SUMMARY**

I am a Computer Science graduate from the University of Sydney, where I completed a thesis on Meta-Learning in Natural Language Processing (NLP). I've completed a wide range of data analytics projects through internships at Telstra, including customer conversion prediction to enhance a marketing campaign, and working with internal developers to create an interactive database visualisation. I also have three years of experience in Machine Learning through research and coursework at University, model development and deployment at Telstra, and research in NLP at CSIRO.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Advanced Studies (Honours) (Computer Science)** University of Sydney

86 WAM | Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

- - Honours thesis: The Applications of Meta-learners to Few-Shot Incremental Learning
  - Coursework: Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning, Advanced Machine Learning
  - Through research I learnt valuable skills including hypothesis creation and testing, assumption validation, understanding academic literature, designing solutions to complex problems and communication and presentation of technical material to both experts and laymen

# **Bachelor of Computer Science with Distinction**

89 WAM | Feb 2018 - Dec 2020

University of Wollongong

- Global Honours Scholar, which funded an exchange year in Singapore and Dubai
- Coursework: Machine Learning Algorithms and Applications, Linear Algebra and Groups, Advanced Engineering Mathematics and Statistics

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### **CSIRO** | STUDENT RESEARCHER

Dec 2021 - Present

- I've learnt a new field, Information Retrieval, and reimplemented the SOTA base retrieval method from the TREC2021 Clinical Trials track. I also developed an improved, 10x smaller model with similar effectiveness
- Trained the 3 billion parameter T5 model on a computing cluster with slurm, pytorch lightning and deepspeed
- Tested our in-house API and reimplemented several baseline neural re-ranking methods with it as examples for a demonstration paper under review. Code is available here

#### TELSTRA | Data Analytics and Management Summer Vacationer

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

- I performed feature engineering for large amounts (1-5Gb) of unstructured event data with Numpy and Pandas
- Then trained an ML model to perform time series classification on the event data using Tensorflow
- I optimised the model for the particular business problem, focusing on the precision metric, and assisted in deploying the model to production

#### **TELSTRA** | DATA ANALYST INTERN

Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

- I developed a customer conversion forecasting model to increase the effectiveness of an advertising campaign
- I extracted training data from a large database, using customer purchases and demographic data as features
- The model identified a customer segment 6x more likely to purchase a product next month. I then deployed it to AWS for use in production

#### TELSTRA | BIG DATA INTERN

Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

- I developed visualisation software to help internal teams understand our complex database structure
- I retrieved data with SQL and Spark and extracted features with Pandas
- Then created an interactive graph with D3.js, and improved it based on user feedback

#### SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, C++, JavaScript, Java, R, Bash

Libraries: Pytorch, Pytorch Lightning, Transformers, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib

**Technologies:** Teradata, Slurm, Git, AWS Sagemaker

Machine Learning: Deep Learning, NLP, Statistics, Linear Algebra, Optimization, Multi-Dimensional Calculus

Natural Languages: English (Native), Japanese (Intermediate)